原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译     克里斯  海云生  kathy567
翻译     527泡芙  子V  TracyOY
校对     布塔
时间轴   西·查  Jenny  caroline  紫夏  壬虚浪影
后期     渔夫
总监     布塔
♪ 男孩们总是告诉我 ♪
♪ The boys always told me ♪
♪ 每一个洞 ♪
♪ Every hole ♪
♪ 都是他们的 ♪
♪ Was a goal ♪
♪ 目标 ♪
♪ For them ♪
♪ 但只有一个洞 ♪
♪ But just one hole ♪
♪ 是我的 ♪
♪ Will be a goal ♪
♪ 目标 ♪
♪ For me ♪
♪ 想要你落到洞底 ♪
♪ Wanting you down there ♪
♪ 暴露无遗 ♪
♪ Lay bare ♪
♪ 感受无所适从 ♪
♪ Knowing your unfamiliarities ♪
♪ 我想把你吃掉 ♪
♪ You're something I want to eat ♪
♪ 但你告诉我肉体淫荡又低劣 ♪
♪ But you told me meat was carnal and cheep ♪
♪ 很抱歉你低劣又暴力 ♪
♪ I'm sorry you're cheap and violent ♪
♪ 我还想把你吃掉 ♪
♪ And something I want to eat ♪
♪ 净化 ♪
♪ Purify ♪
♪ 洗净我 ♪
♪ Bath me ♪
♪ 还记得上次我把你带到边缘 ♪
♪ When was the last time I brought you to the brink ♪
♪ 躺在你身边是我们唯一的不敬 ♪
♪ Lying beside you was our only profanity ♪
♪ 被海水包围  口渴却不能饮 ♪
♪ Thirsty in seawater I can't even drink ♪
♪ 让我到达 ♪
♪ Let me get there ♪
♪ 让我到达  让我到达 ♪
♪ Let me get there, let me get there ♪
♪ 让我到达 ♪
♪ Let me get there ♪
♪ 让我到达  让我  让我 ♪
♪ Let me get there, let me, let me ♪
♪ 让我到达 ♪
♪ Let me get there ♪
♪ 净化 ♪
♪ Purify ♪
♪ 让我到达  让我到达 ♪
♪ Let me get there, let me get there ♪
♪ 净化 ♪
♪ Purify ♪
金  属  之  声
露露
Lulu!
露
Lou.
别弄了
Stop.
露  该起床了
Lou, it's up time.
起床了
Up time.
-知道了  -起来吧
- Yeah. - Come on.
别赖床了
Come on, stop that.
我们得赶紧准备了  记得吗
We got to get right to it for grizzle. Remember?
好吧
Okay.
我给你做了蔬果昔
Yo, I got some smoothie for you.
你肯定讨厌喝
You're gonna fuckin' hate it.
但很健康
But it's healthy.
想来点吗  我可不推荐
Want some? I wouldn't recommend it.
恶心极了
It's disgusting.
好了  懒货
Okay, poops.
该跳舞了
Dance time.
好莱坞热片
棒
Yes!
不要吗
No?
不要  好吧
Nah? No? Okay.
♪ 我愿为爱赴汤蹈火 ♪
♪ And I would do anything for love ♪
♪ 但他不愿那样做 ♪
♪ But he won't do that ♪
歌里他不愿意做的是什么事
What's the thing that he won't do in that song?
还剩什么他不愿意做的
What's left for him to not do?
肛交
Anal.
♪ 不不 ♪
♪ No, no ♪
♪ 但他不愿那样做 ♪
♪ But I won't do that ♪
我以前经常想象杰夫·高布伦是我爸
I used to imagine Jeff Goldblum was my dad.
看他演的《变蝇人》  我就想
Saw him in The fucking Fly, I was like,
"我爸一定就长这个样子"
"Yo, that must be what my dad looks like."
好多事就能解释通了  毕竟那家伙太怪了
Also explains a lot, 'cause the dude's fucking weird.
但他长得像我
But he looks like me, man.
-真的是  -没错
- It's true, yeah. - Yeah!
你长得有点像杰夫·高布伦
You kind of look like Jeff Goldblum.
为什么在公共场合用牙签就行  但用牙线就不行
Why is it okay to, like, use a toothpick in public but not floss?
你试过吗
Have you ever tried that?
-在公共场合用牙线剔牙  没  -在公共场合用牙线
- To floss my teeth in public? No. - To floss in public.
你就在餐桌上  然后拿出...
Like, you're just at the dinner table, you just pull out some...
我以前经常想象自己的葬礼
I used to imagine my funeral a lot
-小时候上数学课时  -太有趣了
- when I was a kid... at school in math. - Fun!
我常常幻象我的葬礼
I used to daydream about my funeral.
然后痛哭流涕
Then I'd make myself cry!
我想我会选择火化
Uh, yeah, I think I'd get cremated.
你呢
What about you?
火化
Cremated...
或者给鸟当饲料
or, like, just fed to the birds, you know?
其实现在你可以
Well, you know, now you can get
把骨灰放进文身颜料里
ashes put into tattoo ink.
-把我的脸文在你背上  -你的脸
- My face on your back. - Your face?
文在小丑那里
Where the clown is.
-什么  -没错
- What? - Yeah.
♪ 吓人的小丑脸 ♪
♪ Scary clown face ♪
♪ Scary clown face. ♪
黑色双陆棋
我们不用都拿出来
Yo, we don't need to... we don't need to put 'em all out.
我知道  但我们要摆满一些
I know, but we just need to fill 'em up a little bit.
-好的  -不错
- Okay. - That's good.
你想拿出一些不同的款式吗
You want to put out... put out some different ones?
这个一定大卖
That's the face of a sale.
好了  这件要多加五十块钱  因为
Okay, this one costs, uh, 50 bucks extra because...
-这是原创艺术品  -我要在上面吐口水
- It's an original artwork. - I'm gonna spit on.
-五十块...  -得卖一百了
- A $50... oh! - Okay, a hundred bucks.
得一万了
That's ten grand.
-你们试音了吗  -还没
- Did you guys sound-check? - No, not yet.
我们是五点
We're going on at...
-上台吗  -玛格丽特试音了吗
- 5:00? - Did Margaret sound-check yet?
你试音了吗
Yo, you sound-checked yet?
还没  不太想动
No. Not looking forward to it.
吓坏了
Terrified.
我的一半设备都坏了
Half my shit is broken down.
没错  我们都能修
钟表  手机  电视  机车  珠宝  皮革
他的听力大概只剩
It's... it's probably a two out of ten
两成左右  他甚至...
in terms of his hearing. He can't...
他连跟我交流都有困难
He's having trouble even communicating with me.
这...
It-it's...
我得去看医生吗
I got to see a doctor?
他现在就可以帮你检查
He... he can see you now.
-什么  -他现在就能帮你检查
- What? - He can see you right-right now.
-现在吗  -对  我...
- Now? - Yes, I-I...
露露  抱歉我得出来一趟  宝贝
Hey, Lulu. Uh, sorry I had to run out, baby.
我有点事得处理
I got to deal with some shit, okay?
别担心  好吗
Don't worry about anything, okay?
斯通先生
Mr. Stone?
好
Oh, yeah.
这个音量怎么样
Okay, how is that volume?
这个音量够大吗
Is the volume loud enough?
很好
Good.
你能听见吗
Can you hear me?
-什么  -你能听见我说话吗
- What? - You can hear me okay?
-音量大小  -我能听见
- Volume-wise? - I can hear you.
好
Okay.
我会读几个词
I'm gonna say these words.
请你跟我重复
I want you to repeat them back to me.
先从右耳开始
I'm gonna start with just your right ear.
好吗
Okay?
贝斯
Bass.
混乱
Mess.
汽车
Car.
拖把
Mop.
喧闹
Noisy.
搜寻
Search.
喉咙
Throat.
-丢  -鱼
- Ditch. - Fish.
说话
Talk.
戒指
Ring.
扫把
Broom.
细菌
Germ.
生命
Life.
队伍
Team.
盖子
Lid.
这是你的测试表  鲁本
This is your chart, Ruben.
在你能听到的音量下
Now, as far as the volume that you can hear,
你的右耳听力水平是28%
you, on your right ear, were 28%,
左耳水平是24%
and on your left ear, you were 24%.
-什么  -你的左耳
- It's what? - In the left ear,
听力水平是24%
you came in at 24%.
好
Okay.
不管我把测试音量调到多大
No matter how loud I made the test--
就算音量破格  你也还是听不见
I could have put it at 11-- you were still going to miss
我说的词里的70%到80%
70% to 80% of the words that I said.
好
Okay.
这可不妙
That is not good.
嗯  我能看出来
Yeah, I see that.
所以
So, what...
我们该怎么做
What can we do about it?
我该怎么恢复听力
How do I get it back?
这个...
Well, um...
你得明白一件事
you have to understand something here.
不管这是因为
Whether or not this is related to
你经常接触噪音
your exposure to noise
还是因为自身免疫
or it's an autoimmune issue
这都不重要
doesn't really matter.
我明白我有问题
I understand I got a problem.
我是在问你该怎么做
I'm asking you what I can do about it.
首先你能做的就是
Well, what you can do about it first
彻底避免接触大音量噪音
is to eliminate all exposure to loud noises.
然后我们再做一些检查来确诊
And then we can run some tests and we can determine exactly
你的耳朵到底怎么了
what is going on with your ears.
如果确诊了  我们就能讨论下一步措施
And if we do, then we can have our other conversations.
我们就能什么
We can have what?
有一些植入设备可以绕过耳蜗
Well, there are implants that bypass the cochlea.
你说植入设备
You said implants?
-对  -管用吗
- Yes. - Those work?
对于听力严重受损或者
For people with severe hearing loss or
完全失聪的人来说  确实有用
complete deafness, yes, they help.
那就这么办吧
Well, then let's do that.
没那么简单
Well, it's not that simple.
这是个很耗时的过程  而且花费不菲
Uh, it's a very involved process, and it's quite costly.
要花多少钱
How much is it?
花费可达四万到八万美元
Well, they can run between $40,000 and $80,000,
而且保险不报销
depending, and they are not covered by insurance.
好
Okay.
那...
And, um...
你什么时候能做
Like, when-when can you do it?
现在有货吗
You got 'em in stock now?
斯通先生  你的听力
Mr. Stone, your hearing
正在急剧衰退
is deteriorating rapidly.
我说的对吗
Am I right?
在接下来的几天
And over the next few days,
甚至几小时里  还会继续恶化
or even hours, it's going to continue.
而你已经损失的听力
And the hearing that you have lost
是没法恢复的
is not coming back.
你必须明白
You have to understand
你的首要任务
your first responsibility
是保护现在仅存的听力
is to preserve the hearing you have.
鲁本  搞什么
Ruben, what the fuck?
-我什么都听不见  -什么
- I can't hear anything. - What?
我什么都听不见
I can't hear anything.
会恢复吗
对  会恢复的
Yes, it'll come back.
我得...
I have to...
就是做个手术
There's, like, a surgery.
什么
What?
很简单  没什么的  就是把植入设备
It's simple. It's all it is. There's an implant.
放进脑袋里
They put it in your shit.
就像...
It's like a...
听力会恢复的
Okay, it'll come back.
没事的  露
It's fine, Lou.
大概要四万到八万  但是...
It's, like, 40 grand, 80 grand, whatever, but it's...
会恢复的
it'll come back.
在那之前  我们就继续表演  好吗
Till then, Lou, we just keep going, okay?
-不  不  -露  听我说
- No. No. - Lou. Listen to me.
我们明天试试  看看情况如何
Let's play tomorrow, let's see what it's like.
我们试试  好吗
Let's try it, okay?
我来打节拍
I'm gonna be like a click track.
你跟着我唱
You can play to me.
-不行  -你可以调整...
- No. - Huh? You can adj...
会不太一样  但就是这么回事  露
It's different, but it is what it is, Lou.
露  我们...我们的巡演都安排好了
Lou, we have a t... Lou, we have a tour booked.
-这不安全  -我们的巡演都安排好了
- It's not safe. - We have a tour booked.
-我们的巡演都安排好了  露  -不
- We have a tour booked, Lou. - No.
-这不重要  这不重要  -我们有巡演
- It doesn't matter. It doesn't matter. - Yes, we do.
-这不安全  这不安全  -我们的巡演都安排好了
- It's not safe, it's not safe. - We have a tour booked!
-鲁本  -我就知道
- Ruben. - I fucking knew it.
能给我支烟吗
You got a smoke, please?
这太荒唐了
This is ridiculous.
他睡了
He's sleeping.
赫克特
Hi, Hector?
我是露
Hi. This is Lou.
鲁本现在...有点麻烦
Ruben's having a bit of... a bit of trouble right now.
-他...  -赫克特  你好吗
- He's... - Hey, Hector, what's up?
他有点听力问题
He's got some hearing problems.
对  我可以把电话给他
Yeah, I mean, I can put him on,
但他听不见你说的话
but he won't be able to hear you.
好
Okay.
跟他说  跟他说
Talk to him. Talk to him.
赫克特  你好吗  兄弟
Hey, Hector, what's going on, man?
我是鲁本
It's Ruben.
我也想说很高兴听到你的声音
I'd say it's good to hear your voice,
但你说的话我一个字也听不见
but I can't hear a fuckin' word you're saying right now.
所以这毫无意义
So this is completely pointless.
露想让我给你打电话  因为我抽了支烟
Lou wanted me to call you because I had a cigarette.
是不太好  不太理想  但是
You know, not great, not ideal, but...
考虑到目前的情况相当操蛋
considering the circumstances, which are pretty fucked up,
这也完全是可以理解的
you know, understandable.
我觉得可以理解
I'd say understandable,
除了露以外  大家应该都能理解
for everyone apart from Lou, it seems.
我没问题  兄弟
I got this, bro.
我知道你大概想问我现在情绪如何
I know you'd probably be asking me if I'm steady right now,
头脑清不清楚
if I'm feeling level.
不是特别清楚  但还行
Not completely, but I'm cool.
你大概会说当自己不再幻想
You'd tell me serenity is something you get
改变过去后  人就会获得内心的平静
when you, uh, stop wishing for a different past.
兄弟  我爱你  老兄
Bro, I love you, man.
我的经纪人要把手机拿回去
Oh, my manager wants the... wants the phone back,
所以我不说了
so I got to go.
好  爱你  兄弟
Okay, love you, bro.
对  他一个字也听不见
Yeah, he- he can't hear a word.
他又听不见  你带他去互助会有什么用
Well, if you get him to a group, then how is he gonna hear?
好
Okay.
好  谢谢  赫克特  谢谢你
Okay, tha- thanks, Hector, thank you.
什么时候  什么时候
When? When?
好  行  我会把音量调大
Okay, yeah, I'll make sure it's on loud.
好  非常感谢  谢谢
Okay, thank you so much. Thank you.
好  再见
Okay, bye.
他会再打过来
He's gonna call back.
他说了什么
What did he say?
写下来  告诉我他说了...
Write it down. Tell... what did he...
"会再打过来"
"Call back."
他会再打过来  就这样
He's gonna call back - that's all?
该死的赫克特
Fuckin' Hector.
我们现在怎么办
What are we gonna do now?
你想怎么做  露
What do you want to do, Lou?
妈的
Fuck this.
是赫克特
It's Hector.
对  他在
Yeah, he's here.
不是太好
Not so good.
好
Okay.
好  你说的是什么...
yeah, what- what... what is it and...
什么  有什么计划
What? What's the plan?
我们在密苏里州  要花几天才能到
Well, we're- we're in Missouri, so that's gonna take a few days.
我不太清楚
I don't... I don't really know.
不不不  我们马上就出发
No, no, no, we'll leave right away.
好
Okay, yeah.
好  谢谢
Okay, thank you.
非常感谢  我真的很感激你
Thank you so much. I really, really appreciate it.
谢谢
Thank you.
好  我会告诉他
No, yeah, I'll tell him.
好
Okay.
再见
Bye.
说了什么
What?
他找了个地方
He's found a place.
失聪儿童区
是他吗
Is that him?
鲁本
Ruben.
你好  抱歉  我不会手语
Hi. I don't... I'm sorry, I don't know that.
我是鲁本
I'm Ruben.
这是露
Yeah, this is Lou.
你好  我是露
Hi. I'm... I'm Lou.
抱歉  我要读唇语
I'm sorry, I read lips.
我叫露
M- My name is Lou.
-露  我是乔  -你好  乔
- Lou. I'm Joe. - Hi, Joe.
-介意我跟他聊聊吗  -不介意
- You mind if I borrow him for a minute? - No.
好  我们聊的时候
All right, you mind watching my beast here for me
你能帮我看着狗吗
while we have a talk?
好吧
Well, okay.
露  这是路易
Lou, this is Louie.
它是我的助听犬
He's my hearing dog.
它告诉我你们到了
He let me know you were here.
它的名字取自59年白袜队球员
I named it after Louie Aparicio
-路易·阿帕里西奥  -好
- from the White Sox in '59. - Okay.
要想跟它打好关系
You want to be best friends with him,
-就给它吃这个  -好的
- give him one of these. - Oh, sure.
-好吗  -好
- Okay? - Yeah.
那个...
Yo, what about...
露  你来吗
Lou, you coming?
不  你去吧
No, no, you.
-你确定吗  -确定
- You sure? - Yeah.
-我不会花太久  好吗  -好
- I won't be long, okay? - Okay.
乖乖的
You be a good boy!
好
Okay.
测试
Test.
好了
Okay.
这个能用
So, it works.
你看这个可以吗
Is this okay for you?
可以  你能听见我说话吗
Yeah, can you hear me?
不能  我读你的唇语
No. No, I'm gonna read your lips.
可能会漏掉一些  但我尽量  好吗
I might miss some things, but I'm gonna try, okay?
-好  -你说话尽量吐字清晰
- Okay. - Just try, try to speak clearly.
好
Yeah.
你好吗  鲁本
How are you, Ruben?
我还好
I'm okay.
你有毒瘾吗
You're an addict?
有
Yeah.
哪种毒品
What sort of drugs?
我吸哪种毒品
What'd I take?
来者不拒
Everything.
主要是海洛因
Mainly heroin.
海洛因
Heroin.
你失去听力后  想过要吸毒吗
Have you thought about using since you lost your hearing?
今天不太好过
Today is not a good day.
我头脑不清楚
I'm not thinking clear today.
聊聊我的情况吧
Let's talk about me.
我酗酒
I'm an alcoholic.
越战的时候  一枚炸弹在我身边爆炸
I lost my hearing in the Vietnam War
我因此失去了听力
when a bomb exploded near me.
我还记得那枚炸弹爆炸时
I still remember the music I was listening to
我在听的音乐
when that bomb went off.
在那之后  我失去了一切
After that, I lost everything else -
我的妻子  我的孩子
my wife, my kid.
注意  鲁本  那不是因为我聋了
Not because of being deaf, mind you, Ruben.
而是因为酗酒
It was the beer.
你戒毒多久了
How long you been clean?
四年了
Four years.
四年
Four?
你现在需要帮助吗
And you need some help right now?
我应该去看看露
Yo, I should check on Lou.
你们俩在一起多久了
How long you two been together?
四年
Four years.
你搞音乐  对吗
You play music, right?
-不  -不
- No. - No?
现在不搞了
No, not anymore.
我得先去装植入设备
Not until I get the implant.
-植入设备  -对
- Implant? - Yeah.
抱歉  你了解现在的植入设备吗
Sorry, you know about these implants they got now?
就是  他们有植入设备
It's like... it's like, uh... th- they have implants.
我知道  对
I know. Yes.
很贵
Expensive.
对  谢谢  确实很贵
Yeah. Thank you. Yes, they are.
好了
So...
你要明白
You should understand that, uh,
这是个失聪人士社区
this is a Deaf community.
不只是有我的项目  我们属于
Not just my program, but we're part
你要明白  鲁本
这是个失聪人士社区  不只是有我的项目
我们属于一个更大的失聪人士社区
一个更大的失聪人士社区
of a larger Deaf community.
我的项目  和参加项目的人
And my program, and the people in it,
都从这个失聪人士社区中受益良多
they benefit tremendously from that Deaf community.
我们同他们合作
We work with them,
他们也同我们合作
and they work with us.
但有一点很重要
But it's very important,
如果你想留在这里
if you want to be here,
你要明白  我们想要解决的
to understand that we're looking for a solution to...
是思想的问题
to this...
而不是听力的问题
not this.
你叫露也进来吧
Why don't you go invite Lou in here?
好
Sure.
露
Lou!
他想跟你谈谈
This guy wants to talk to you.
好
Okay.
我觉得你现在应该
Well... I think it's important
留在我们这里  鲁本
that you stay here with us right now, Ruben,
学点手语
learn some sign language,
踏踏实实地适应
find some solid ground.
你怎么想
What do you think?
听起来很好
Man, it sounds great,
但我们现在没多少钱
but we don't have a lot of money right now.
我们的教会有时会资助需要帮助的失聪人士
Well, sometimes our church sponsors deaf people in need,
而现在
and right now,
你符合条件  鲁本
you fit the bill, Ruben.
我们真的不是那种
We're really not
-会去教堂的人  -抱歉  我得读...
- churchgoing people. - Sorry, I-I read...
抱歉  鲁本  我得读唇语  我没...
Sorry, Ruben, I read lips. I can't...
你刚才说什么
What'd you say?
我们两个都不信教
We're not religious, either of us.
对宗教完全不感兴趣
Very much not into religion.
无意冒犯
No offense, you know.
宗教与此无关  鲁本
Religion plays no part in this, Ruben.
教会帮助
The church helps
有需要的人  而不是信教的人
people in need, not religious people.
重要的是你想留在这里
The important thing is that you want to stay here.
好吧
Yeah.
露
Lou?
你觉得鲁本现在需要帮助吗
Do you think Ruben needs help right now?
你要明白如果...
You understand, if, uh...
鲁本打算留在这里
Ruben were to stay here,
他就得靠自己了
he'd have to do it on his own.
大家都住在与外界隔绝的房子里
Members live in a house separate from the outside world.
与外界没有联系
No contact to the outside world,
没有电话
no phones.
我发现无论怎样  这都是最好的办法
I've found that in all cases, that's the way it works best.
慢一点  好吗
Yo, hold up a minute, okay?
让我看完  好吗
Let me catch up. Okay?
你能帮鲁本下这个决心吗  露
Can you help Ruben commit to that, Lou?
你想...你想先试几天吗
You want... you want to try this for a couple days?
我们有自己的家
We have our own home.
我们可以住在房车里
We can stay in the RV.
不  很遗憾  我们这里
No, I'm sorry to say, that's not the way
不允许这样  鲁本
that it works here, Ruben.
那就有问题了
Well, that's a problem, then.
这段时间里你有地方可去吗  露
Do you have anywhere you can be during this time, Lou?
就这样吧  不说了
Yo, that's that, man. We're done.
不说了
We're done.
谢谢你抽出时间  兄弟
Thanks a lot for your time, bro.
非常感谢  好吗
Appreciate it, okay?
我们走了  宝贝  走吧
We're out, baby. Let's go.
露
Lou...
我觉得我们还是应该去
I'm thinking we should still go hit
参加达顿的演出
our fuckin' show in Dayton.
好吗  我可以...我可以看你的提醒
Okay? I can... I can fuckin' watch you for cues.
我知道上次有点不顺  但我们...
I know it was rocky last time, but we did...
我们没提前说好
we weren't on the same page.
现在你知道怎么回事了  我可以看着你
Now you know what's up, I can fuckin' watch you.
我对谱子了如指掌
And I know this shit inside out.
好吧  我肯定能搞定
Okay, yo. I can fuckin' make it work
直到我们赚够钱做手术
until we have enough for surgery.
好吗
Okay?
我们会成功的
We're gonna get there.
说真的  我们可以去的
Yo, seriously, we're good to go.
露
Lou.
我会搞定这事的
Hey, I'll deal with this shit.
我会搞定的
I'll deal with it.
你知道我会的  只是钱而已
You know I fucking will. It's just money.
你知道的  对吧
You know that, right?
过来
Come here.
鲁本
Ruben!
鲁本  鲁本
Ruben! Ruben!
住手
Stop it!
鲁本
Ruben!
露  看着我  我不会
Lou, look at me. I'm not going back
回那个鬼地方的  好吗
to that fuckin' place, okay?
我担心你
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
我...
I'm...
那你就支持我啊
Well, then fuckin' support me.
怎么样  支持我啊  露
How's about that? Fuckin' support me, Lou.
你不想待在这里吗
You don't want to be here?
-我当然想  -我就知道
- Of course I do. - I knew it.
我就知道  我就知道会这样
I fuckin' knew it. I fuckin' knew this was coming.
我就知道
I fuckin' knew it.
是因为那张破专辑吧
This is about the fuckin' album, huh?
怎么回事  你有更好的邀约了吗
What happened? You get a better offer?
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
-说什么呢  -我听不见
- What are you saying? - I can't hear...
我听不见  我他妈听不见
I can't hear you. I can't fucking hear you!
你懂吗  我听不见  我他妈聋了
Do you understand me? I can't. I'm fuckin' deaf.
我他妈聋了
I'm fucking deaf!
听不见
No fucking hearing!
好吗  好吗
Okay? Okay?
你现在需要的是支持
不  我需要的...我需要的是拿把枪塞进我嘴里
No, what I need... what I need is a fucking gun in my mouth.
我需要的是拿把枪塞进我嘴里
What I need is a fucking gun in my fucking mouth!
好吗
Okay?!
对不起
Look, I'm sorry.
露  我只是有点混乱
Lou, I'm just fucked up a little.
我只是...我需要点时间思考
I just need a little... I need a minute to think.
好吗
Okay?
肯定还有别的办法
There's got to be another way.
露
Lou?
喂
Hello?
真的吗
Oh, really?
是谁
Who is that?
好吧  我得去准备了
Okay, well, I need to get ready.
好  不用  我打车吧
Okay. No, I'll get a cab.
好  没事的
Yeah, it's fine.
好  再见
Okay, bye.
怎么了
What's going on?
我要坐飞机走了
I'm getting on a plane,
你要回那个地方
and you're gonna go back to that place.
慢着  好吗  等一下
Just slow down, okay? Slow down.
等一下  老兄  我们马上就好
Yo, chill, dude. We're gonna be a minute.
等一下  好吗
Just chill. Okay?
先等一下
Just slow down a minute.
露  露
Lou. Lou.
这太扯了
This is so fucked up.
去了那边谁来照顾你
Who's gonna be looking out for you over there?
-谁来照顾你  -没事的
- Who's gonna look out for you? - It's okay.
-别说是那家伙  -没事的
- Don't say that guy. - It's okay. It's okay.
露  我需要...我需要更好的计划  露
Lou, I need... I need more of a plan, Lou.
-鲁本  -我需要...
- Ruben. - I need...
我需要你支持我  露
I need more from you, Lou.
我需要更好的计划  露
I need more of a plan, Lou.
你不能就这么...
You can't just fuckin'...
天啊  露  别这样
Jesus. Lou, come on.
鲁本  鲁本
Ruben. Ruben.
你伤害你自己
You hurt yourself...
鲁本  你伤害你自己
Ruben, you hurt yourself,
你伤害我
you hurt me.
我也会伤害我自己  我也会伤害我自己
I'll hurt myself, too. I'll hurt myself, too.
别这么说
Don't say that.
答应我
Promise.
说啊  鲁比  不然这一切都白费了
Say it, Rubi, or all of this is for shit.
说啊  答应我
Say it! Promise!
马上回去
Go back there right now.
答应我  快说
Promise, say it!
-我答应如果你...  -不  说啊  答应我
- I'll promise if you... - No, say it, promise.
回那个地方去
Go back to that place.
我...只有...我需要...
I... only if... I need...
我需要你等我
I need you to wait for me.
好吗  你是我的唯一  露  你是我的心肝
Okay? You're it for me, Lou. You're my fuckin' heart.
你是我的唯一
You're it for me.
好吗  你得等我
Okay? You got to wait for me.
妈的
Fuck.
听我说  听着  听着
Listen to me. Listen, listen.
你到了那里  要...
When you get there, I need you to...
你要给我写信  好吗
I need you to write to me, okay?
好吗  你会写信跟我报平安吗
Yeah? Will you write me and tell me you're okay?
答应我
Promise me?
听着  如果...
And listen, if it's...
如果不行  你就赶紧回来
If it's bullshit, you just get your ass back here.
我会恢复的  我发誓
I'll fix it, I swear to God.
你知道我会恢复的
You know I'll fuckin' fix this.
没多难  好吗
This is not that hard, okay?
赶紧回来
Just come back here.
-我爱你  -你是我的心肝
- I love you. - You're my fucking heart.
好吗
Okay?
妈的
Motherfucker.
Motherf...
妈的
Fuck.
Motherfucker.
妈的
Fuck.
Motherfucker.
你好吗
What's up?
你要我的车钥匙
You want my car keys?
我要的时候你得还给我  好吗
If I ask for 'em back, I want 'em back, okay?
手机不能给你
We're not doing that.
你的名字
Your name.
我叫鲁本
My name's Ruben.
我有毒瘾
I'm an addict.
我已经戒毒四年了
I have four years clean now.
抱歉  我...
I'm sorry I don't...
不会手语
talk sign language.
就这些
That's it.
我叫沙希姆
My name is Shaheem.
我对海洛因上瘾
I'm a heroin addict.
妈的
Fuck.
鲁本
在这里大家都有任务
鲁本  学习适应失聪的生活
干什么
What?
好
Okay.
现在学习《数学》课本第127-128页
我知道
I know, right?
我不会...
Um, I don't...
抱歉
Sorry.
黛安
鲁本
Ruben.
声音
好的
Okay.
好
Yeah.
我马上就来
Uh, I'm coming.
等我一下
Okay? One minute.
我...我马上回来
I-I'll... I'll be back.
正在解密
鲁比鲁比鲁比鲁比鲁比
鲁比  我到这边了  感觉怪怪的  请跟我报个平安
知道你在勇敢面对给了我活下去的动力  我说真的
即使你心灰意冷  也要为了我鼓起勇气
别忘了这一点
我爱你  鲁比
妈的
Fuck.
乔
Oh, hey, Joe.
你刚才在做什么  鲁本
What was that all about, Ruben?
是说房顶吗
Oh, with your roof?
我在帮你修屋顶
I was fixing your roof.
有一块屋檐...
It's, like, one of the eaves is...
我想帮你修好
I was trying to fix your roof.
你在这里不需要修任何东西
You don't need to fix anything here.
好吧
Okay.
我给你布置了
I've got a little, uh...
一个小任务  好吗
assignment for you. Okay?
你每天都起得很早吧
You get up early, right?
是的  挺早的
Yeah, pretty early, yeah.
早上5点半
I'll have hot coffee
我会为你
waiting for you
准备好热咖啡
at 5:30.
够不够早
Early enough for you?
我说不好  也许吧
I don't know. I guess.
好吧  那就5点
Okay, 5:00.
我还会
And I'll, uh,
为你准备一个房间
provide a room for you.
做什么
What for?
在那个房间里你什么也不用完成
And there's nothing that needs to be accomplished in this room.
我想让你做的只是
All I want you to do is just...
静坐
sit.
我所要求的只是  你坐不住的时候
All I ask is if and when you cannot just sit,
就拿起笔和纸
you turn yourself to the pen and paper
我会为你准备好纸笔
that I'm going to supply for you.
我希望你
And I want you to...
写东西
write.
你写什么  怎么写
Doesn't matter what you write, how you write,
拼写对不对  这些都不重要
whether it's spelled correctly.
哪怕你就是
Or if it's just a big...
瞎写
mess.
我不在乎
I don't care.
不会有人看的
No one will read it, okay?
但我要你一直写下去
But I want you to keep writing
不要停下
continuously without stopping
直到你感觉自己能...
until you feel like you can...
坐得住了
sit again.
-一定得写东西吗  -写  没错
- Does it have to be writing? - Writing, yes.
不能画画  要写东西
No drawing. Writing, yes.
如果到了某个时候
And if... sometime in the future,
你觉得这对你来说有点太难了
it feels like it's a little bit too difficult for you,
你就来找我
you should come and find me.
我会在我的公寓里
I'll be in my apartment
跟你做同样的事  好吗  鲁本
doing the same thing as you, okay, Ruben?
我也会在写东西
I'll be writing, too.
好吧
Okay.
很好
Mmm, nice.
很好  很好  很好
Nice, nice, nice.
真他妈蠢
So fucking stupid.
这他妈太蠢了
It's so fucking stupid.
你个蠢货
You fucking idiot.
真是个大蠢货
What a fucking idiot.
你觉得他还好吗
You think he's okay?
你还好吗
You okay?
-不好  -没感觉好点吗
- No. - Not feeling better?
过来
Come on over.
看那些花
Look at those flowers.
他很快
He's quick.
好了  过来  朋友
All right, come here, my friend.
瞧  我就知道在他那里
See, I knew he had it.
A  B  C
A, B, C,
D  E  F
D, E, F,
G  H  I  J
G, H, I, J,
K  L  M  N
K, L, M, N--
R  S  T
R, S, T,
U  V  W
U, V, W,
X  Y  Z
X, Y, Z.
他赢了
He won.
-不  不  他赢了  -是平手
- No, no, he won. - It was close.
不  是他赢了  你要是想的话可以再比一次
No, he won. You can go again if you want to.
再来  再来  再来  再来
Again! Again! Again! Again!
A  B  C  D
A, B, C, D,
E  F  G  H  I
E, F, G, H, I,
J  K  L  M  N
J, K, L, M, N,
O  P  Q
O, P, Q--
R  S  T
R, S, T,
U  V  W
U, V, W,
X  Y  Z
X, Y, Z.
好啊
Yes!
瞧见没
See?
干得好  你做到了
Good job! You did it!
不  我以为
No, I thought...
你不是说你很聪明吗
I thought you said you were smart.
但你老婆和女儿
But your wife and your daughter
好点了吧
are better, right?
瞧  他知道了
See? He knows!
他已经知道了
He already knows.
我不喜欢毛剃光的
I don't like it completely shaved.
我喜欢有一点毛的
I prefer it with a little hair.
也别太多毛
Whoa, not too much.
自然点  懂了
Natural, got it.
修剪整齐那种  懂吗
Trimmed and all, ya know?
好极了
Lovely.
她是谁
Who is she?
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
你想文在哪里
Where do you want it?
这里
Right here.
我喜欢
I like it.
很好  谢谢
Cool. Thank you.
我的错
My bad.
看着我
Watch me.
慢慢来
Slowly.
今天我感觉自己有点老了
I feel a little bit old today.
你本来就老了
You are old.
我喜欢你的手语名
I love your name sign...
鲁本
Ruben.
你第一天到这里的时候
That first day you were here,
你让我想到了猫头鹰
you reminded me of an owl.
-猫  头  鹰  -猫头鹰
- O-w-l? - Owl.
去你的
Fuck you.
对这里很多人来说
And you've become very important
你已经变得非常重要
to a lot of people around here.
你知道吗  是真的
You know? It's true.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想给你提供
I'd like to offer you a...
一个机会
a way that
让你能继续留在我们这里
maybe you can continue on here with us.
我想你已经开始考虑
I imagine you're starting to think
自己的未来了吧
about the future a little bit?
-未来吗  -未来
- Future? - Future.
我知道我在考虑
I know I am.
不过  我确实觉得
But, uh... I do think there's a way
有办法让你留在这里工作
you could maybe stay and work here,
也许是参与我的项目
uh, maybe with my program,
也许是...
maybe...
在学校帮助孩子们
with the kids at school.
也许两种都行
Maybe both.
不管怎样
Anyway...
你...
you, uh...
你考虑一下
you think about it, you know?
狄斯科耳狄亚
录音样带
新专辑
三个月后发行  混蛋们
黑色双陆棋
废物91发布
露在巴黎  刚看了露在巴黎的演出  她太棒了
千载难逢好机会近距离看她  我惊呆了  这姑娘太牛逼了
我拍了视频  链接在此
打开视频
什么鬼
What the fuck?
她吗
Her?
对
Yeah.
没错
很性感
Cute.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think, huh?
Yo, what do you think?
这些
This?
全部吗
All?
对
Yeah.
等等  很简单的
Wait, yo, it's easy.
很简单的  只要慢慢来
It's easy. Just... slowly.
这是为了她
It's for her, huh?
It's for her.
我们需要钱  我们需要钱
We need money. We need money.
这是为了我们
It's for us.
我跟你说实话
I'm leveling with you.
这是为了她
It's for her.
这些
For-for this?
这些  记住
For this, remember it's, uh...
收现金
it's, uh... cash.
好吗  不收支票
Okay? Not check.
好
Cool.
你没问题吧
You okay?
确定吗
Sure?
听觉矫正
我们的听觉矫治专家
朱丽叶·卢阿斯
是普林斯听觉矫治吗
Hi. Is that Prince Audiology?
你能听见我说话吗
Can you hear me?
下午好  有什么能帮助您的吗
能听见  请告诉我您的姓名
我叫斯通  鲁本·斯通
It's Stone, Ruben Stone.
鲁莽的鲁  本来的本
R-u-b-e-n,
斯通  斯文的斯  通常的通
Stone, S-T-O-N-E.
我要确认预约
I'm confirming an appointment.
好的  斯通先生  请您...
好  我可以等
Yeah, I can hold.
听我说
So, listen.
-你说什么  写下来  -好
- What did you say? Write it down. - Yeah, yeah.
我听不见你说话  写下来
I can't hear you. Write it down.
我有个提议
I got a proposition for you.
什么提议
What's that?
我就这个价卖给你
What if I give it to you at this price...
但附加一个条件如何
but on one condition?
我可以选择在八周内再次联系你
I have the option of coming back to you within eight weeks.
行吗  从你手上赎回来
Okay? I get to buy it back off you
再多给你10%的利息
for ten percent more than this.
但一切都得维持原状
But everything has to be in its current condition.
现在什么样到时候就要什么样
Everything has to be exactly like it is now.
你觉得可以吗
What do you think?
你何必这么做呢
Why would you want to do that?
老兄  我听不见你说话  我聋了
Dude, I can't hear you. I'm deaf.
要么接受  要么拉倒
So it's... take it or leave it.
你怎么决定
What's it gonna be?
乔
我没事
我明天就回来
不用担心
鲁本
手术很顺利  鲁本
我们绕过了你的耳道
所以这段时间你完全听不到声音
四周后你要回来激活设备
你回来了
You're back?
坐吧
Have a seat here.
谢谢
Thank you.
我做了
I did the deed.
做了什么
The deed?
手术
Surgery.
你从哪弄来的钱
How'd you get the money?
我卖了房车和其它有的没的
I sold my RV and other shit.
-好吧  -听我说  乔
- Okay. - Look, Joe,
我现在真的不想做太多解释
I really don't want to explain myself right now.
可以吗
Okay?
是时候了  好吗
It's time. Okay?
是时候了  我得做点什么
It's time. I got to do something.
好吗
Right?
我在拯救我的人生
Trying to save my f-fuckin' life.
这就是我在做的事
So, that's what I'm doing.
行吗  因为没人会救我
Okay? No one else is gonna save my life.
不是吗
Right?
如果我坐在这里无所事事
If I just sit here and diddle around,
我能得到什么  我会一无所有
what am I gonna have? Nothing.
好吗
Okay?
还有这一切
And all this shit?
重要吗  有什么意义
Like, what does it matter? What does it matter?
反正都会过去的
It just passes.
如果我消失了
If I disappear,
有谁会在意
like, who cares?
没人会在意
Nobody cares, man.
真的
Seriously.
但没关系
Yo, and that's okay.
这就是人生
That's life.
我是认真的  好吗
No, for real. Okay?
都会过去的
It just passes.
他妈的说过去就过去了
It just fucking... fucking passes.
我在想
I wonder, uh...
你在我的书房待了那么多个上午
all these mornings you've been sitting in my study,
坐在那里
sitting,
你有没有
have you...
感受到过
had any...
片刻的
moments of...
平静呢
stillness?
因为你说得对  鲁本
Because you're right, Ruben.
世界在不断前进
The world does keep moving,
同时它也是个
and it can be a damn...
很残酷的地方
cruel place.
但对我而言
But for me...
那些平静的时刻
those moments of stillness,
那个地方
that place, that's the...
就是天国
kingdom of God.
那个地方
And that place
永远都不会抛弃你
will never abandon you.
但是
But...
我看到你已经做出了选择
I see you've made your choice.
是吗
Right?
是的
Yeah.
我也衷心希望
And I sincerely hope
你的选择能带给你幸福  鲁本
that it brings you happiness, Ruben.
谢谢
Thank you.
我在想  乔  不知道能不能...
I was wondering, Joe. I don't know if it's possible...
我需要钱
but, uh, I need money
赎回我的房车
to... just to buy back my RV.
就这样
You know?
我和露
You know, me... me and Lou.
那是我们的住所
This is where we live.
是我们的家  我们的家
It's our home. Our home.
我绝对会还钱给你
And I can... I can totally pay you back.
只是
Just, uh...
现在时间紧迫
Now I got an issue with time.
鲁本
Ruben.
我不知道你让自己陷入了何种境地
I don't understand the situation that you've put yourself in,
但是
but...
在我看来
from where I'm sitting...
你现在的行为举止像是毒瘾犯了
you look and sound like an addict.
不是  我没有
No, I don't. Yo, no.
我没有
I'm not... It's not...
犯毒瘾
Not an addi...
我没事
It's fine. Okay?
我的情况很好  好吗
My situation, it's cool. Okay?
真的  我女友她爸很有钱
Seriously, my girlfriend's dad is rich,
他可以给我钱
he can give me... give me the money.
这没什么的
Okay? This is nothing.
根本就不是事儿
You can't imagine how nothing this is.
真的
Seriously.
我太蠢了  很抱歉我问你借钱
I'm fucking stupid. I'm-I'm sorry to ask.
对不起  好吗
I'm sorry. Okay?
好
Okay.
拜托  我能在这里
Please, can I stay here for just...
再住三四周吗
three, four weeks?
等他们
Till they...
激活设备
activate?
鲁本
Ruben.
你也知道  这里的人
As you know, everybody here
都坚信
shares in the belief that
失聪不是残疾
being deaf is not a handicap.
不需要修复
Not something to fix.
这一点对这里的人很重要
It's pretty important around here.
这些孩子
All these kids...
我们所有人
all of us,
每天都需要将此
need to be reminded of it
铭记在心
every day.
我的机构以这一信念为根基
And my house is a house built on that belief,
以信任为根基
and built on trust.
当那份信任被打破
And when that trust is violated,
会产生后果
things happen.
而我不能容忍
And I can't have that.
我还有许多其他人
There are too many others
需要关照
to consider.
所以
And so,
鉴于你目前的状况
in your current state, at this time...
我只能请你今天就打包好行李
I'm going to have to ask you to pack up your bags today
另找住处  鲁本
and find another place to be, Ruben.
行
Cool.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
好
Okay.
开始了
Here we go.
你能听见吗
Can you hear me?
再说一遍
Say again.
你能听见吗
Can you hear me?
听起来怎么样
How does it sound?
听起来怪怪的
Sounds weird.
好的  我来调整一下
Okay, well, let's try making an adjustment.
现在如何  还行吗
How about now? How's that?
不行
That's bad.
就是...
It's...
不行
It's bad.
你能形容一下你听到的声音吗
Do you want to describe what you're hearing?
就是...
It's...
又高又尖
It's, like, high. High.
你能调一下吗
Can you change the...
我可以试着再做一下调整
Well, I can try and make another adjustment.
现在怎么样
How's that?
好的
Okay.
鲁本  这不是你记忆中的声音
Ruben, this is not sound like you remember,
你脑内的植入设备
and it's the implants in your head
让你的大脑以为
that's tricking your brain into thinking
你真的听见声音了
that you're actually hearing,
但实际上你的听力并没有恢复
when in reality your ears aren't working still.
我建议你在接下来的几周里
So, I would suggest that you take it easy
放轻松
for the next few weeks and...
就是...
just...
适应一下你听到的声音
get adjusted to how things sound.
慢慢来
And just take your time.
哪位
Oui?
你好
Bonjour?
你好  那个...
Yeah. Hi. Is that...
露在家吗
Is... is Lou there?
什么  你是谁
Hein? C'est qui?
你是谁
Who... who is this?
我是鲁本
This is Ruben.
谁
Qui?
鲁本
It's Ruben.
你好
Bonjour...
-我是鲁本  -请进
- Ruben. - Come in.
你肚子饿了吧  鲁本
You are hungry, Ruben?
饿了吧
Yes?
露易丝不在
Louise is not here.
你能听见了吗
You are hearing?
Y-You are hearing?
能  我做了个手术
Yeah. I-I had an operation.
是吗
Yes?
这是什么  我瞧瞧
What is this? Wait.
这太好了  露易丝告诉我你想做这个手术
That's very good. Louise told me your wish for this.
那么
And so...
你又回去打鼓了吗
So, you're back to your drums now?
还没有  我得  我得
Not yet. I got to... I got to...
我得先处理一些事情
I got to deal with some stuff first, you know?
得把一些事情安排妥当
Just got to... got to settle some things.
好的  安排
Yes, settle...
安排什么
Like what?
就是
You know, just like...
重回以前的生活  还有一些钱的问题
just getting back into it and also some financial stuff.
-好的  -我得把一切都处理好
- Yes. - You know, I just got to figure it all out.
好
Yes.
露易丝知道你来了吗
And Louise knows that you're here?
不  她不知道
No. No.
要给她个大惊喜  对吗
So, it's a big surprise, oui?
露易丝最近很忙
Well, Louise has been quite busy, you know?
我们要开个派对
We're doing a party, so...
她今晚会回来
she'll be back home tonight.
这是一定的
That's most certainly.
你要不要...我给你做点鸡蛋
You want... I'm going to make you some eggs.
不用  我不吃了
Oh, no, I'm good.
需要我帮忙吗
Do you need any help with any of this?
不  不用
No, no.
你得吃点鸡蛋
You need some eggs.
谢谢
Thanks.
鲁本  你是在哪里长大的
Where did you grow, Ruben?
我在哪里长大的
Where did I grow up?
-对  -很多地方
- Yes. - Like, all over.
德克萨斯州  加利福尼亚州
You know, Texas, California,
亚利桑那州  弗吉尼亚州
Arizona, Virginia.
很多地方
Yeah. All over.
为什么这么多地方
Why so many places?
因为...
It was... like...
我妈是军队护士
my mom was a nurse in the military.
所以她总是要跟着部队辗转
You know? So she kept moving around.
你的父亲也是吗
And your father, too?
不是
No.
我是说  我不知道
I mean, I don't know.
我明白了
I see.
我得坦诚告诉你
I must be honest, I...
鲁本  这些年来  我并不总是
did not always have good feelings for you, Ruben,
对你有好感
all these years.
说实话我感觉像是
I confide it is like if one...
被人偷走了宝贵的东西
had stolen something precious.
你能明白吗
You understand?
但我知道并不是你把露易丝从我身边抢走的
But I know it's not you that took Louise from me.
是她的母亲
Her mother did that.
她离开我的时候带走了露易丝
She took Louise when she left me.
她自杀的时候又一次让她与我疏远
And she took her again when she killed herself.
那时露易丝只能回家
And Louise must have come back home then,
但她非常恨我
but she was hating me so much.
我能怎么办
What could I do?
而你  你...
And you... you...
你给了她一个逃离我的去处
Well, y-you gave her a place to go.
然后
Then, and...
这是好事
this is a good thing.
你能明白吗  我当时不怎么喜欢你
Don't you see, I didn't like you much at the time,
但如今我感谢你
but now I thank you.
这就是我想说的
I want to say to you that.
总之
But anyhow,
你看到露易丝现在过得很好
you're gonna be so happy to see how Louise
一定会很开心的
is going great now.
这才是最重要的事
And that's the most important.
不是吗
Isn't it?
好
Okay.
你能听见吗
Can you hear me?
能  清清楚楚
Yeah. Loud and clear.
让我看看你  露露
Look at you, Lulu.
天啊
Holy shit.
瞧瞧你
Look at you, huh?
-怎么了  -你看起来不一样了
- What? - You look different.
你没挠自己
No scratching, huh?
是啊
Oh, yeah.
太好了
That's good.
会感觉很奇怪吗
Does it feel weird?
是的  看起来奇怪吗
Yeah. Does it look weird?
不会
No.
不奇怪  看起来很棒
No, it doesn't. It looks really neat.
这太疯狂了
So crazy.
你怎么做到的
How'd you do it?
只是施了点魔法
Just worked some magic.
我得和你说一下
I have to talk to you about it.
我不得不卖了些东西
I had to just move some things around.
露易丝  下来好吗
Louise, tu descends?
理查德有没有告诉你今晚有个派对
Did Richard tell you about this party thing tonight?
对了  他说过
Shit, yeah.
我得去处理一些事情
Yeah, I just have to go and sort some things out.
挺好的  没关系
No, it's great. It's cool.
去忙你的吧
Go do your thing.
好
Okay.
你有什么需要的吗
Do you need anything?
没有  不用
No, I'm good.
我就在楼下
I'll just be downstairs.
-你好吗  -这是我男友  鲁本
- What's up? - Ruben, mon petite ami.
你好吗
What's up?
-你说什么  -你好吗
- Come again? - How are you?
你好吗
How are you?
你吃东西了吗
Did you get some food?
吃东西了吗
Get some food?
-嗯  -是吗
- Yeah. - Yeah?
我想许个愿
I would like to make a wish.
我希望我的女儿和我一起唱一首歌
I would like my daughter to sing a little song with me.
爸爸  不要
Papa, no.
我有权许这个愿  今天是我的生日
This is my right... It's my birthday!
来吧
Come.
你们中有些人
Some of you knew
认识露易丝的母亲
Louise's mother,
也知道我曾为她写过歌
and know that I wrote songs for her.
写过许多首
Many.
这首是你小时候的最爱
And this was your favorite when you were little.
你记得吗
Do you remember?
♪ 色彩皆褪去 ♪
♪ S'effacent, les couleurs ♪
♪ 在这房间里 ♪
♪ Entre quatre murs ♪
♪ 这份爱如此疯狂 ♪
♪ Cet amour, c'est fou ♪
♪ 你未曾体会 ♪
♪ Que tu n'as pas connu ♪
♪ 这份爱又一次杀死我 ♪
♪ Cet amour me tue, encore ♪
♪ 我的爱 ♪
♪ Mon amour ♪
♪ 我已死去 ♪
♪ Je meurs ♪
你还好吗
You okay?
挺好的
Yeah.
抱歉
Sorry.
我得喝点水
I just need some water.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
还好吗
Yeah?
没事  只是有点干燥
Yeah, it's just a little dry in here.
今晚的派对
That was... that was...
挺棒的
pretty cool tonight.
你唱得太好听了
You sounded fucking great.
-得了吧  -怎么了
- Yeah, right. - What?
别告诉我你唱的时候没动感情
You're telling me you weren't feeling it?
-你当时很投入  -好吧
- You were in it. - Well, yeah, well, that's...
毫无疑问  你那么唱歌好听极了
Straight up, you sounded amazing singing like that.
那是我爸写的歌
It's my dad's stuff, but...
你现在会说法语了
And you're speaking French now?
老天  只会一点点
Oh, my God, barely.
我都不知道你会说法语
I didn't know you could do that.
我都快忘光了  不过
Well, I've mostly forgotten, but...
开始慢慢捡起来了
it's coming back a little.
我刚才还在想  你记得吗
Yeah, I was thinking, like, do you remember...
记得这个地方吗
you remember this place at all?
之前不记得  但是
I didn't, but...
我自己都不知道有些事情
so disconcerting the things that
还在记忆中留存  挺让人困惑的
your memory holds onto without you knowing.
我也不知道  我...
I don't know, my...
我妈从没跟我说起过这个地方
my mom and I never really talked about this place.
我脑中只有模糊的奇怪印象  但是
It was always some weird, dreamy idea, but...
现在慢慢开始想起来了
I mean, now it's come back a little.
好
Right.
嗯
Yeah.
我跟大家讲了我们吉普赛人式的生活
I told everyone about our little gypsy life together.
我很怀念
I miss it.
我们得重回那种生活
We got to get back into it.
我们要回到那种生活
You know? We got to get back on it,
我们要找回那种
we got to get back in the fuckin'...
那种状态  对吗
in the groove, huh?
你说呢
Don't you think?
我得把房车的事搞定
I got to go get the Airstream sorted.
搞定什么
What do you mean "sorted"?
就是  就是有一大堆事情要做
I just, I just got a shit ton of things to do.
-是吧  -嗯  是说巡演的事吗
- You know? - Right. Like, with the tour and stuff?
-是啊  巡演什么的  -嗯
- Yeah, the fuckin' tour, everything. - Yeah.
我们得重回以前的生活
Like, we just got to get back on it,
一切都要继续
you know, everything.
专辑  巡演
The album, the tour...
还有...是吧
the-the... you know?
嗯
Yeah.
没关系  露
It's okay, Lou.
什么
What?
没关系
It's okay.
什么没关系
What's okay?
你拯救了我
You saved my life.
你让我
You made it...
你让我的人生变得美好
you made it beautiful.
所以没关系
So it's okay.
什么
What?
你为什么说这些
Why are you saying this?
你也拯救了我  鲁比
You saved my life, too, Rubi.